A Guide to the papers of Thomas D. Pawley 1912-1962
Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
A guide to the Thomas D. Pawley Papers 1912-1962
Special Collections and Archives, Johnston Memorial Library, Virginia State University
1985-35
The Pawley papers consist of some business correspondence and other Memorabilia. Mr.Pawley was a member of the faculty at Virginia State University. Acc. #1985-35
The Thomas D. Pawley papers were given to Virginia State University as a gift.
Administrative Information
Access
There are no restrictions.
Acquisition Information
A gift from the Pawley family.
Biographical/Historical Information
Thomas Pawley a graduate of Amherst and Harvard was professor of English at Virginia State College from 194 until 1947. During his tenure he coached the debating team and authored an english text book entitled A Modern Advanced English Gramma in 1930. A street was named for him at the University in 1986.
Scope and Content Information
Mr. Pawleys papers are made up primarily of Correspondence both personal and businesss. In addition there are a few printed items such as programs and degrees of family members. On a particular note are several folders included by Thomas Pawley, Jr documenting his articles about John M. Gandy and Luther Porter Jackson.
Series Description
Series I. Minutes Minutes of several campus organizations which Pawley was affiliated with.
Series II. Correspondence The bulk of this series documents pawleys correspondence with other members and administrators of the faculty during his tenure. In addition, some corrospondence relating to Pawleys book which was pulished in 1930.
Series III. Literary This material was added to the papers by Thomas Pawley Jr. There is some correspondence and sketches of both Luther Porter jackson and John M. Gandy which Pawley was asked to contribute for the Dictionary of American Negro Biography.
Series IV. Printed Programs, flyers, and degrees of Thomas Pawley and his wife, Ethel J. Pawley.
Series V. Photographs. Photograph of Virginia State University class of 1925.
Contents List
- Minutes
  - Campus Organizations 1935, 1936, 1946 (Box-folder 1:1)
- Correspondence
  - Family 1931, 1938 (Box-folder 1:2)
  - Virginia State University 1943 (Box-folder 1:3)
  - Virginia State University 1942-1944 (Box-folder 1:4)
  - Virginia State University Proposal Programs 1941 (Box-folder 1:5)
  - Correspondence 1965-1973 (Box-folder 1:6)
  - Correspondence book-work business 1934, 1947 (Box-folder 1:7)
- Literary
  - Writing 1928 (Box-folder 1:8)
  - Gandy, John M. Sketch by Tom Pawley, Jr. 1914, 1947 (Box-folder 1:9)
  - Jackson, Luther P. Sketch by Tom Pawley, Jr. 1931, 1973 (Box-folder 1:10)
  - Jackson, Luther P. Jr/ Tom Pawley Correspondence 1950, 1973 (Box-folder 1:11)
  - Virginia State College Chapter 10, John M. Gandy n.d. (Box-folder 1:12)
  - Sketch J.M. Gandy, by Tom Pawley, Jr. n.d. (Box-folder 1:13)
  - Sketch-L.P. Jackson, by Tom Pawley, Jr. 1943 (Box-folder 1:14)
- Printed
  - Contract 1930 (Box-folder 1:15)
  - Printed 1942, 1985 (Box-folder 1:16)
  - The Negro History Bulletin n.d. (Box-folder 2:1)
  - The Association for the Study of Negro Life and History n.d. (Box-folder 2:2)
  - Iota sigma Lambda Honorary Society n.d. (Box-folder 2:3)